TOM YISHAY

SOFTWARE ENGNEER/ANALYST

CONTACT

- ★ Amsterdam
- **6** 0613448881
- ✓ tomishay2000@gmail.com
- % https://tomishay.github.io/
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-yishay-6b48721a8/

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a developer and an analyst with expertise in behavioral and processes data with experience of 1.5 years in the tech industry. I like to see myself in the intersection of technical programming/math skills and soft skills such as communication and active listening that I developed during my bachelor's in psychology.

Recently I have been managing the development of the "Quality control" module of JASP with the support of the SKF group and UVA's psychological methodology department. I have made a timeline, developed code, and overlooked the communication in the project successfully launched to hundreds of employees.

I have experience developing statistical tools and analyses (e.g. Six Sigma, descriptions, and multivariant analysis) using QML and R-studio packages such as ggplot2, shiny app, flexbox-dashboard, and more. I am also a passionate writer regarding the academic domain- I enjoy constructing logical arguments supported by real-world data and reasoning. For examples of both, visit my website https://tomishay.github.io/.

I am a big animal lover who cares for the environment we share with nature. I am always glad to learn and expand my knowledge of sustainability and healthy co-existence with the natural world.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer and Project Manager

SKF Group | Sep 2021 - Present, Amsterdam

- Writing, design, and development of the Quality Control module using R and QML.
- Uni tests and GitHub management.
- Data analysis and output verification.
- Presentation and communication of the new tools via slides, video tutorials and live sessions of up to 200 people.
- Management and coordination of the communication between a team of 5 JASP developers and 3 SKF managers.

Software Developer

JASP | Sep 2020 - Sep 2021, Amsterdam

Implementation and development of the "Quality Control" model in JASP using R-studio and QML in a group of 4 students supervised by PhD students from the university of Amsterdam. Contributed to:

- Process capability studies.
- Control charts.
- Measurement systems analysis.

Officer of Communication

Study association VSPA | Mar 2019 - Sep 2019, Amsterdam

First Year Weekend Committee: responsible for all communications between the VSPA and the event location including the coordination of times, equipment, and activities for more than 150 students.

Tour Guide

We are Amsterdam | Dec 2018 - Present, Amsterdam

Guidance and instruction of groups of tourists (up to 40) about the Netherlands' history and culture in English, Hebrew, and Dutch.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Psychology (Psychometrics/ Behavioral data science track)

University of Amsterdam | Sep 2018 - June 2021, Amsterdam

Third-year (Behavioral Data Science track):

- Simulating Psychological Processes (6 EC's; 9)
- Psychology and AI (6 EC's; 9)
- Mathematical Modeling (6 EC's; 8.5)
- Latent Variable Models (6 EC's; 8.5)
- Fundamentals of Methodology (6 EC's; 8)
- Machine Learning & Multivariate Statistics (6 EC's; 9.5)
- Bayesian Statistics (6 EC's; 8.5)
- <u>Thesis:</u> The Role of Emotional Compared to Political Involvement in Attitude Polarization as Modeled by the Cusp (12 EC's; 8)

Second-year:

- Animal Cognition (6 EC's; 9)
- Scientific and Statistical Reasoning (15 EC's; 8.5)
- Fundamentals of Psychology (6 EC's; 9)
- Research and Writing Practicum (6 EC's; 8)

First-year:

- Introductory Psychology and Cognition (12 EC's; 9)
- Research Methods and Statistics (12 EC's; 8)
- Developmental Psychology (6 EC's; 8.5)
- Social and Work & Organisational Psychology (12 EC's; 9)
- Clinical Psychology & Brain and Cognition (12 EC's; 8)
- Test Theory & Practice (6 EC's; 9)

Honors Programme, B.Sc. Psychology

University of Amsterdam | Sep 2018 - June 2021, Amsterdam

Completion of the Honors program of Psychology,

30 extra EC's with a mean score of 8.5 (cum lude):

- Medical psychology.
- Introduction to programming in MATLAB and R.
- Reductionism & Psychology.
- Breaking Borders (interdisciplinary projects).

SKILLS

Programming

R-studio QML MATLAB HTML CSS Python



Data analysis

JASP Multivariate statistics SPSS Minitab



Research

Scientific writing Test construction Presentation



Languages

Hebrew English Dutch French

